Glory Praise Emmanuel

emmaglorypraise@gmail.com +2348179859168 7 Ameahule Street, Eligbolo Port Harcourt, River State

Summary

Excellence drove Front-end Web Developer with over 18 months experience in blending the art of design with the skill of programming to deliver engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging. Ability to communicate and listen effectively and work in a team.

Experience

Web Designer / Front End Developer

Freelance 07/2019 - Present

 Create beautiful, responsive and optimized websites for businesses, brands and individuals

Mentor

Google Africa Developer Scholarship

06/2020 - Present

assist and mentor over 1000 learners on the Mobile Web Development Track in their journey with the program by offering technical help in their courses, monitoring their progress

Web Development Intern

The Roothub • Uyo, Akwa Ibom

12/2018 - 07/2019

- Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement
- Taught Tech101 students HTML, CSS and Bootstrap
- Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues

Technical Skills

- Git
- Javascript
- · Netlify

- · HTML and CSS
- WordPress

Education

Computer Engineering

University of Uyo, Uyo • Uyo, Akwa Ibom

Enrolled 10/2021

- · Vice President(Nationa
- Vice president (Association of Computer Engineering Students)
- Volunteer at Developer student clubs(DSC)
- · Mentor at Techovation Girls Challenge

Tech 101 - Web Development

Roothub · Llvo Akwa Ihom

Best Graduating Student in Web Development	12/2018
Team Lead of Small Group	
Frontend web development Developer circles with Open classroom	Graduated
Learnt HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React	08/2019
Web development ALC 4.0 Learnt HTML, CSS, JavaScript	Graduated 11/2019
Finished as one of the top 1000 finalist	
The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing Google Digital Skills for Africa	Graduated 02/2020
Digital Skills: Social Media	
Accenture - Future Learn	02/2020
 Learned how to effectively use social media for business, how to promote brand, set campaign objectives, how to identify the target audience and the right channels. 	
Languages	
• English	
Other Skills	

- Problem Solving
- Collaboration
- Communication
- Adaptability

Social Media Handles

- Github https://github.com/emmaglorypraise
- Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/emmaglorypraise/
- Twitter https://twitter.com/emmaglorypraise
- Portfolio: https://emmaglorypraise.me/